http://www.hon.ch/en/privacy-policy.html

Contact Us
IntroductionThe Health On the Net Foundation (HON) is committed to honoring and respecting the privacy and anonymity of the individuals using its website(s) and/or services. The purpose of this privacy policy is to inform the individuals about what information HON collects, why the Foundation collects this information, how it is used and how it is protected. This privacy policy applies to all the websites and services owned and/or managed by HON (listed below).
This privacy policy is reviewed regularly to reflect HON's current practices. Collection of personal information and limitationsHON collects personal information only when it is voluntarily provided for a particular service. The information collected primarily concerns communication details, such as names, phone numbers, email addresses, mailing addresses. For the HONcode certification process, the webmaster might provide a login/password in order to access any restricted areas. While personal information is requested mainly during the HONcode certification process, it is also requested of those users submitting a complaint or giving feedback, subscribing to our newsletters, participating in a survey and/or applying for another service we provide.
Any personal information voluntarily provided to HON by users and visitors of HON's websites is kept in the strictest confidence. This information is stored in the HON database. Only HON staff members, and only for the duration of their contracts, have access to the information stored in HON databases. Personal information provided voluntarily is used only for the purposes for which it was provided. HON asks individuals to explicitly consent to their personal information being used for any other reason than the one provided for.Right to verify and have your personal data deletedYou have the right to ask to have access to and verify any personal information HON may hold about you to ensure that it is accurate, as provided by law. To protect your privacy, we take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting you access to, or making corrections to, your personal information. You may opt out altogether of having us collect, use, or disclose your personal information at any time, subject to reasonable notice and applicable laws.
If you wish to withdraw from any of our services, please contact us here.
Please note that communication details cannot be completely deleted during HONcode certification. They can only be replaced and updated.Personal data storage and deletionThe information collected by HON will be removed from HON databases upon your request and when any relationship with HON through the services offered has been terminated.
However, a copy of the personal information collected during HONcode certification will be stored and will be permanently deleted within two years after the removal of the HONcode file from the HONcode database. Disclosure of information to third partiesHON does not share, rent, sell or trade any personal information with any third party. All personal information is kept confidential, unless explicitly agreed otherwise or if otherwise provided by law. No third parties have access to the HON database.Collection of anonymous dataHON collects anonymous data for different services and purposes. This data can be used for technical, statistical and research purposes. HON ensures that all information shared remains anonymous. The anonymous data is subject use in scientific publications.
Anonymous data (including URL addresses and abstracts copied from certified websites and similar information) is collected for all HONcode certified websites and/or for websites that are included in a search engine managed by HON. The impersonal information collected will also be used for research purposes.
By participating in a survey, you consent to HON collecting your personal information (if asked for). When we publish information, we do not disclose any personal information. If the publication includes any identifying details such as your name and address, we will ask for your explicit permission.
Anonymous data is always collected when someone visits a HON website so that we might analyze how users use the website and improve our websites and services. For further information, see below under Cookies / Google Analytics. The HONcode sealHON has developed a dynamic and active HONcode seal which allows for the recording of a website's status in real-time according its compliance with the HONcode principles. This seal shows the last date the website was reviewed and is automatically updated after every review or audit. The seal collects only impersonal information such as your Internet Protocol address, browser type, browser language, etc. which cannot be used to identify you personally. We do not sell, transmit, share or divulge this information to any third party and it is safely stored on the HON Web servers and used only by the HON collaborators and system manager to improve our services.CookiesLike most websites, HON uses “cookies” in order to better serve HON website users. These cookies contain specific information (not identifiable) about you and track your visits to our site.When using our website, you accept the use of cookies. Otherwise, please do not use our service.
What is a cookie?
A “cookie” is a small text file that is sent to your browser and stored on your computer’s hard drive when you visit our site. Each time you use the same computer to access our site, our Web servers will be notified of your visit and in turn we may have knowledge of your visit and the pattern of your usage.
What sort of cookies does our site use?
Some cookies are necessary for the operation of our site. For example, when you choose a language, a cookie will help us recognize you as an existing user and will show you the right information. If you choose to block cookies, some aspects of the site may not work for you.
How do I disable cookies?
Most browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies. You can also delete cookies already stored on your computer.
All cookies have a default expiration date, but you can manage this date yourself and empty the storage.
Different Web browsers may use different methods to manage cookies. Please follow the links below to access the browser manufacturers directly in order to configure your browser settings.
Internet Explorer
Chrome
Mozilla Firefox
Safari
Blocking cookies will have a negative impact on the usability of some websites, but this will not affect your use of our site.Google Analytics The HON website uses Google Analytics to help analyze how users use the site. This tool uses cookies - text files placed on a computer - to collect standard Internet log information as well as visitor behavior information in an anonymous form. The information generated by the cookie about the use of the website (including the IP address) is transmitted to Google. The information is then used to evaluate visitor's use of the website and to compile statistical reports on website activity.
We will never (and will not allow any third party to ever) use this statistical analytics tool to track or to collect any Personally Identifiable Information (PII) of the visitors of the HON site. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. We won't link, or seek to link, an IP address with the identity of the computer user. We will not associate any data gathered from this site with any Personally Identifiable Information from any other source, unless you explicitly provide this information to us.
You can set your browser not to accept HON cookies. Disabling the cookies does not affect navigation on the HON website.
Learn more about Google Analytics Privacy.We decided to anonymize the IP for Google Analytics, changing the last IP information in memory shortly after being sent to the Analytics Collection Network. The full IP address is never written to disk in this case.Summary of cookies
The following cookies are used on our site:
HON ca29ad15654e025d04b0d52e166bb7eb Type : Functionality Description : this cookie is used to know if the user is a visitor or someone logged in. Default expiration time:
when the browsing session ends.
HON 62fcb33e83ad40d8bc5853fd39b7793b Type : Functionality Description : this cookie is used to know which language is chosen by the user when visiting the website. Default expiration time: 1 year
Google Analytics
_ga Type : Performance Description : this cookie is used to distinguish users. Default expiration time: 2 years
Google Analytics
_gat Type : Analytics Description : this cookie is used to throttle request rate. Default expiration time: 10 min
Google Analytics
__utmz Type : Performance Description : this cookie records whether the visitor came from a search engine (and if so, the search keyword used), a link, or from no previous page (e.g. a bookmark). Default expiration time: 6 month
Google Analytics
__utma Type : Performance Description : this cookie stores the amount of visits (for each visitor), the time of the first visit, the previous visit and the current visitDefault expiration time: 2 years
Google Analytics
__utmb Type : Performance Description : this cookie is used to check approximately how fast people leave: when a visit starts, and approximately ends (expires quickly). Default expiration time: 30 min
Google Analytics
__utmc Type : Performance Description : this cookie is used to check approximately how fast people leave: when a visit starts, and approximately ends (expires quickly). Default expiration time: when the browsing session ends.
Tawk-to __tawkUUID Type :
Functionality  Description : This cookie is used to collect information about how the visitor interacts with the live chat function on the website. Temps d'expiration : 180 days.
Tawk.to Discussion ToolOur site offers the Tawk.to online chat tool, a live chat solution provided by Tawk.to Ltd, so you can instantly communicate with our team if you have any questions. Tawk.to uses cookies to help us identify and track visitors who communicate with us. All communications between us and our visitors in this chat are secured by an SSL connection. The conversation log can be saved with your personal profile.
Its use implies the consent of their terms and conditions and their privacy policy, in addition to ours.
You can find all this information about Tawk.to on these pages:
Privacy Policy
General terms and conditions
Data protection and privacyLinks to third party websitesThis privacy policy applies to HON websites and services only. We do not exercise control over the sites listed in our search engines or sites that include HON applications, products or services, or links within our various services (e.g. HONcode certified sites). The other sites may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, collect data or solicit personal information from you. We encourage you to always read the privacy policy of any website you visit. Liability of HONHON does its most to provide trustworthy and reliable information. If you find any mistakes, please notify us as soon as possible and we will try to correct them in the shortest delay possible.
You agree that your use of HON websites is at your own risk. The websites, including all content, software, functions, services, materials, and/or information made available or accessed through websites, are provided "as is," without warranty of any kind. In no event shall HON be held liable for any direct, indirect, incidental, special or consequential damages arising out of or in any way connected with the use of the website or with the delay or inability to use same, or with hypertext or graphic links to third parties, or for any information and services obtained through the website. Applicable lawsHON adheres to Swiss privacy principles and commits to respect the Swiss laws on the protection of personal data.Language of the privacy policyThis privacy policy was initially created in English. If any translation has been provided for your convenience, you agree that the English version of the privacy policy will govern the relationship between you and HON. For any discrepancies between the English language version and a translated version, the English version shall take precedence.Modifications of the privacy policyThis privacy policy can be modified from time to time. We recommend checking this information on a regular basis. Contact usIf you have any questions or concerns relating to this Privacy Policy, please contact us here.For any additional information about the confidentiality of your data, you can send us an email at dpo@healthonnet.org.
Author : Team HON
Last Reviewed : March 2020
© 2020 Health On the Net - Non-Gouvernemental Organisation (NGO) - HON is a non-State actor in official relations with the World Health Organisation (WHO)
Menu
CertificationDiscover the certificationWebsitesMobile applicationsSocial networksUpdatesGDPRCertified websitesToolsNewsContact
